Guide to the George Wells Beadle Papers 1908-1981
University of Chicago Library
Beadle, George Wells. Papers
1908-1981
18.5 linear feet (33 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
George Wells Beadle, professor, university administrator. The George Wells Beadle papers include speeches, correspondence, subject files, inauguration papers, invitations, press releases, newspaper clippings, offprints, calendars, honorary degrees and certificates, photographs, albums, medals and plaques.
Information on Use
Access
The collection is open for research.
Biographical Note
George Wells Beadle, professor, university administrator.
Scope Note
The George Wells Beadle papers include speeches, correspondence, subject files, inauguration papers, invitations, press releases, newspaper clippings, offprints, calendars, honorary degrees and certificates, photographs, albums, medals and plaques.
Series I: SPEECHES, 1961-1976
Series II: INAUGURATION PAPER
Series III: SUBJECT FILES, 1961-1968
Series IV: MISCELLANEOUS
Related Resources
Browse finding aids by topic.
Subject Headings
Beadle, George Wells, 1903-1989-; Beadle, Muriel; College presidents -- Illinois -- Chicago; College presidents -- Inauguration; Speeches
INVENTORY
- Series I: Speeches, 1961-1976
  The speeches in this collection date from February 10, 1961, shortly after George Beadle's election to the Chancellorship on January 5th of that year, to November 8th, 1976, just before Edward H. Levi was inaugurated as the new President November 14th. In October of 1961 the title of the head of the University was changed from Chancellor to President. The collection thus covers George Beadle's entire formal leadership career at the University.
  The speeches pertain both to Mr. Beadle's presidency - to the functioning of the University and its educational aims and processes - and to his work in biology, focussing on genetics and heredity.
  The addresses are listed chronologically, with the title (if there was a formal title), and the audience. The list was prepared by Mr. Beadle's secretaries initially, and only checked and updated by the Special Collections staff.
  The actual forms of the speeches vary; in some cases only notes have been preserved, although most speeches are represented by typed, final copies. Occasionally some correspondence is present concerning the meetings for which the speeches were presented.
  The collection is open for scholarly research, not subject to the 25 year restrictions of the "Regulations Governing Access to Records of the Central Administration in the University Archives" because Mr. Beadle's speeches were public at the time of their delivery.
  - List of Mr. Beadle's speeches, kept by his secretary (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Remarks, University of Chicago Alumni of Greater Los Angeles Reception, February 10, 1961 MIT Centennial Celebration, "The Use of Genetic Specifications," April 6-9, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Presentation of Atoms for Peace Awards to Sir John Cockcroft, MIT, April 6, 1961 Civic Dinner, May 3, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Inaugural Address, May 4, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Inauguration Luncheon, May 4, 1961 Convocation Address, "The Open Mind," June 9 & 10, 1961 All-Alumni Luncheon, June 10, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 24th Annual Reading Conference, June 27, 1961 Acceptance of Chronic Disease Hospital (not delivered), July 12, 1961 Economic Club of Chicago, "The Genetics of Population and Growth," September 21, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Executives Club, September 29, 1961 New York Alumni, October 25, 1961 Washington, D. C. Alumni, October 27, 1961 Dedication of the New Orangeburg, N. Y. Plant of Schwartz Bio-Research, Inc., "Some Comments on Science, Industry, and the Academic Life," October 28, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Acceptance of Norwegian Scroll (Norwegian Professorship), October 29, 1961 University of Chicago Service League, November 20, 1961 Modern Language Association, December 28, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Trustees' Dinner Speech, "Thoughts of a New President," January 10, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - TV Program No. 451, "Science in Action" (Station KRON TV Channel 4 - San Francisco), "The Miracle of Genetics," January 29, 1962 E. B. Films, Inc. (Film shot in Conference Room), March 1962 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Chicago Commonwealth Club, "Academics in the Cause of Man," March 1, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - First Jayne Memorial Lecture, "From Mendel to Watson and Crick," March 7, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Chicago Sunday Evening Club, "Living Philosophies," March 18, 1962 Charter Day Address, UCLA, "Academics in the Cause of Man," March 27, 1962 IBM Meeting, "The Teachers and The Taught," April 23, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - AAUP Annual Meeting, "Federal Dollars, Academic Salaries, and Related Phenomena," April 27, 1962 Welcome to the United Nations Representatives, May 16, 1962 Members of the Order of the "C", June 7, 1972 Convocation Address, June 8 & 9, 1962 Illinois Manufacturers Association, June 8, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - University High School Convocation Address, "Why Are You, You?," June 15, 1962 American Hospital Association, "The University's Role in Education for the Health Professions," June 19, 1962 New York Alumni, September 20, 1962 Welcome to Newcomers, September 30, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Remarks to Representatives of Government, to Industry, and to Academic Institutions (Mayor's Committee for Economic and Cultural Development), October 11, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Julius Rosenwald Centennial Observance, October 15, 1962 Dedication of Bauer and Black Polyken Research Centre in Barrington, Illinois (Kendall County), "Health and Disease - Industry, Academics, and the Government," October 25, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - ASA University Conference on the Science and Technology of Space Exploration, "Response from the University Viewpoint," November 1, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Omaha Chamber of Commerce Luncheon (notes), November 9, 1962, University Senate, Mandel Hall, "State of the University," November 6, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Illinois Conference on Higher Education, Allerton Park, "Keynote Address," November 15, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Industrial Sponsors Autumn Conference, "Research Administrators in a University," November 12, 1962 Central Association of Science and Mathematics Teachers, Inc. (St. Louis), "Molecules and Men," November 23, 1962 Dedication of Joseph P. Kennedy, Jr. Memorial Laboratories for Mental Health, November 29, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 20th Anniversary of Atomic Age, Luncheon, December 1, 1962 Regional Conference of School Administrators on New Science Curricula, "The New Understanding of Science," December 2, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1962 Jayne Memorial Lectures, Lecture I "Mendel to Watson and Crick," March 7; Lecture II "In Molecular Terms," March 14 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Jayne Memorial Lectures, Lecture III "Evolution and Nature of Man," March 21 A collection of the 3 Jayne lecture texts, published by the American Philosophical Society in 1963 under the title of "Genetics & Modern Biology" (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Trustees' Dinner Speech, "Thoughts of An Old President," January 9, 1963 The Third Annual Dewey F. Fagerburg Lecture, "The New Biology and the Nature of Man," January 25, 1963 Robie House, Opening Ceremony for Fund-Raising Drive, February 4, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 59th Annual Meeting, Chicago Association of Commerce and Industry, February 6, 1963 Conference on Institutional Cooperation or the Public Service (Dinner), February 7, 1963 The Great Challenge, Series for 1963, CBS TV Network, George Wells Beadle Member of Symposium, "Science in the American Democracy," February 10, 1963 Illinois Institute of Technology Chapter of Sigma Xi, "The Rosetta Stone of Life," February 15, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - University of Chicago Biology 112 Lecture Notes, "Genetic Information," March 7, 1963 Argonne Program, McCormick Place, March 14, 1963 Luncheon, Hosted by Secretary Rusk State Department, "Some Recent Advances in Biology," March 25, 1963 House Subcommittee on Appropriations, "Reimbursement of Costs of Government Sponsored Research," March 27, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - College of Wooster Luncheon, "What the Molecules Say," April 21, 1963 Corporate Support Fund Dinner Remarks, April 22, 1963 Sigma Xi Lecture, Upjohn, Kalamazoo, "The Oldest Living Language," April 24, 1963 Alumni Foundation Dinner, April 30, 1963 First Annual Presentation of Service Awards Honoring Staff of University of Chicago Hospitals and Clinics and Clinical Departments, "Importance," May 8, 1963 Orthogenic School Ground Breaking, Luncheon Remarks, May 8, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Space Month, May 8, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Inaugural Dinner for W. Allen Wallis, University of Rochester, May 16, 1963 Notes for Rochester, NY, Alumni Meeting, May 17, 1963 National Association of Physical Plant Administrators of Universities and Colleges, "Welcome," May 20, 1963 Mellon Institute, "The Evolution of Molecular Communication and the Nature of Man," May 23, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - National Foundation Meeting, "Dividends of Free Inquiry in Scientific Research," May 29, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Convocation Address, "On the Importance of Diversity," June 7 & 8, 1963 University of Miami Commencement, "So Much To Do, So Little Time," June 11, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Corporate Support Luncheon Remarks, June 14, 1963 National Science Teachers Association, "Symposium on Scientific Literacy," July 18, 1963 Welcome to Freshman and Graduate Students, September 1963 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - State-Federal Conference on Mental Retardation, September 20, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Nuclear Applications Conference, September 26, 1963 Appearance at New Dormitory (Gag Dinner), September 29, 1963 American Council on Education Annual Meeting, October 3, 1963 Convocation Address, Brandeis, October 6, 1963 SSA Ground Breaking, Dinner, October 17, 1963 Alumni Luncheon, New York, October 23, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - State of the University Address, November 5, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Citizen's Board, November 13, 1963 Telephone Lecture (notes), "Molecular Basis of Heredity," November 26, 1963 Argonne Dedication of ZGS, December 4, 1963 Statement on NASA Electronics Research Center, December 16, 1963 Speech Honoring Rabbi Simon Rodfei Zedek Congregation, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Trustees' Dinner for the Faculties, January 8, 1964, Hyde Park Business & Professional Association, January 28, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - California Institute of Technology, Dedication of Beckman Auditorium, February 25, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Pre-Med Club (notes for talk), April 7, 1964 Joseph P. Kennedy, Jr. Foundation Gift, April 8, 1964 AAUP Notes for Informal Talk, April 8, 1964 Nutrition Foundation Luncheon, "Dogs, Flies, Bread Mold and Nutrition," April 23, 1964 WVCB Broadcast (remarks taped), May 1, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - R. W. Harrison Memorial Service, Northwestern University, "The First Amendment: Its Academic Significance," May 21, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Kansas State University Commencement Address, "Nature and Man's Mind," May 31, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Convocation Address, "What's in the Mind," June 12 & 13, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - NEC Industry Advisory Committee (Breakfast talk), 1964 College & University Personnel Association, "Introduction of Muriel," August 2, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Fifth National Cancer Conference, September 19, 1964 Brown University Symposium, "Future Directions of the University," September 28, 1964 Newcomers' Meeting, October 11, 1964 Vassar College, Alan Simpson Inauguration, October 16, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - University of Chicago Corporate Committee Dinner, October 20, 1964 13th Annual Conference of School Administrators, "Genetic and Educational Aspects of Cultural Change," October 22, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - American Physical Society, "Costly and Specialized Research Facilities: How to Use them," October 23, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 1964 National Youth Conference on the Atom, "Recent Developments in Genetics, November 5, 1964 to November 7, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - State of the University Address, November 10, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Biomedical Career Conference Notes, The University of Chicago, November 14, 1964 Southeastern Michigan Junior Science and Humanities Symposium, November 20 & 21, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Trustees' Dinner for the Faculties, January 14, 1965 American Marketing Association "Man of the Year" Awards Dinner, January 15, 1965 Meadville Theological School, January 19, 1965 The College, The University of Chicago, "One Gene - One Enzyme," February 2, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Johns Hopkins Convocation Address, "Man and His Inheritance: Biological and Cultural," February 22, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Chicago Medical Society Talk Notes, March 3, 1965 University of Illinois Medical School, Gehrmann Lectures, March 31, 1965 Albert L. Hopkins Lecture Hall Dedication, University of Chicago Law School, April 19, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Speech, Wahoo, Nebraska, August 26, 1965 Frank S. Whiting Award Luncheon, September 17, 1965 Loyola University, Stritch School of Medicine, 50th Anniversary, "Genetics and Modern Medicine," October 8, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Columbia University, Opening Lecture on "The Relationship between the Biological and Physical Sciences," notes, October 11, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Campaign Remarks to Trustees, October 20, 1965 State of the University Address, November 9, 1965 Massachusetts Institute of Technology, International Symposium in the Life Sciences and Dedication of new building for the Center for Life Sciences, December 2 & 3, 1965 American Association for the Advancement of Science at the University of California, Berkeley (abstract), "Genetics and Cultural Change," December 28, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Trustees' Dinner for the Faculties, January 12, 1966 Alumni Cabinet and Alumni Fund Board, March 1, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Convocation Address, June 10 & 11, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Dedication of Wyler Children's Hospital, August 28, 1966 Welcome to Undergraduates and Graduate Students, Fall 1966 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Campaign Regional Leadership Meeting and Luncheon, September 15, 1966, Laird Bell Quadrangle Dedication, October 12, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - University's Campaign Leadership Conference, October 14, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Conference on "The Arts and the Public" (welcoming), October 16, 1966 Dedication of Philip Pekow Hall, October 20, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - State of the University Address, November 1, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Address to the Students, November 18, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Society of Mayflower Descendants (State of Illinois), November 18, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 10-11)
  - Nobel Prize Dinner, Citizens Board, December 1, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Wabash College Inauguration, December 3, 1966 Chicago Regional Campaign Leadership Meeting, December 13, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Trustees' Dinner for the Faculties, January 1, 1967 Inborn Errors of Metabolism (Liberal Arts), February 10, 1967 Joseph Priestly Celebration, Dickinson College, "Genetics and Cultural Evolution," March (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Pre-Convocation Luncheon Address, March 17, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Notre Dame University, "Genes, Mind and Man," March 20, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - 75th Anniversary Convocation, May 5, 1967 Alumni Luncheon, June 10, 1967 Announcement of Edward Levi as President-Designate of the University, September 14, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Campaign Leadership Dinner, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, September 26, 1967 Welcome to Undergraduates and Graduate Students, Fall 1967 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Visits to Pittsburgh Companies (Westinghouse, Koppers, Pittsburgh Plate Glass, etc.), October 4 & 5, 1967 Welcome to Newcomers, October 8, 1967 Groundbreaking, Regenstein Library, October 23, 1967 Campaign Leadership Luncheon, Dallas, Texas, October 26, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - The State of the University, November 7, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - The State of the University, November 7, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Cincinnati Alumni Meetings, November 15, 1967 Indianapolis Alumni Meeting, November 16, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Stanford University Herrin Biology Center Dedication, November 30, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 25th Anniversary of First Nuclear Chain Reaction, December 1 & 2, 1967 Campaign Leadership Luncheon, Minneapolis-St. Paul, December 6, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Trustees' Dinner for the Faculties, January 10, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Mothers' Aid Executive Committee Meeting, Lying-in Hospital, January 17, 1968 Biochem 302, "Inborn Errors of Metabolism," January 17, 1968 Thomas Alva Edison Foundation St. Paul, Minnesota, "The Macalester Conference," "The Significance of Biology in the Affairs of Man," January 20, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Dinner for William Benton, February 1, 1968 American Association for Neurological Surgeons (substituting for Mayor Daley), April 9, 1968 Pre-Convocation Luncheon Address, March 15, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Kansas City Alumni, May 3, 1968 Poultry Breeders Association, Kansas City, May 4, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Visit of King of Norway, May 7, 1968 Mothers' Aid Dinner, May 18, 1968 Medical Alumni Fund Dinner, May 23, 1968 Meeting with Alumni and Prospective Donors in San Francisco, June 1968 Pre-Convocation Luncheon, June 7, 1968 Cobb Hall Dedication, June 7, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Convocation Address, June 7 & 8, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Dinner Honoring Shah of Iran, June 14, 1968 Dedication of Pahlavi Building, June 15, 1968 Notes for Talk to House of Delegates, American Medical Association, June 16, 1968 Oak Park Alumni, June 19, 1968 Mr. and Mrs. Beadle's Meeting with Students and Teachers in NSF Program, June 25, 1968 Brain Research Foundation, June 27, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Wisconsin State University, July 17, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 12th International Congress of Genetics, Tokyo, Japan, August 1968 Notes on Greeting Students, Fall 1968 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Institute of Medicine, Jesse Horton Koessler Memorial Lecture, "The Double Helix in Health and Disease," October 15, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Mount Sinai School of Medicine, City University of New York, "Medicine in a Changing World," October 20, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Kent State University, Dedication of Cunningham Hall, November 2, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Members of the Senate, "The State of the University," November 5, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Southern Illinois University, November 8 & 9, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous papers and reprints (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - University of Nebraska, School of Medicine, "The Role of Research," April 18, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - American College of Physicians, Chicago, "The Impact of Biology on the Health of Man," April 23, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Institute for Biomedical Research, "Heredity and Environment in Cultural Changes," May 7, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Institute for Biomedical Research, "Biology, Culture and Education," May 31, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Nobel Conference, June 30, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Commencement, Menlo School and College, "Diversity Among Men," 1970 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - AMA-ERF, Institute of Biomedical Research and the University of Chicago, "Medical Responsibilities of an Urban University," n.d. (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Butler University, "Past, Present, and Future," n.d. (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Institute for Biomedical Research, AMA-ERF, "Genetics Today," n.d. (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - "Genetics and the Quality of Life" (AMA), n.d. 2 speeches with no title, date, or occasion noted, both given by George Wells Beadle Notes from a speech, "Adventures with Plants," George Wells Beadle, at Pomona, March 14, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Series II: Inauguration Paper
  - Manual and mailing directions (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Lists (Box 9, Folder 2-3)
  - Statistics (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Letters of Acceptance (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Trustee Committee (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Faculty Committee (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Press Releases (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Inaugural Banquet, May 3, 1961, McCormick Place (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Convocation and Inauguration, May 4, 1961, Rockefeller Memorial Chapel (includes copy of his speech) (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Inaugural Luncheon, May 4, 1961, Hutchinson Commons (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Beadle's supper party, May 4, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Complete set of printed material, invitations, etc., for the inauguration (Box 10)
  - Letters of congratulations (formal) (Box 10)
  - Certificates (Box 11)
  - Letters of congratulations (formal) (Box 11)
  - Inauguration of Chancellor/financial statements (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Inauguration of Chancellor (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - George Wells Beadle, Outside comments on Inaugural speech, May 4, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - George Wells Beadle, Press releases (complete set) (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Series III: Subject Files, 1961-1968
  - Alaska, trip to, summer 1967 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, annual meeting, Berkeley, California, Mr. Beadle's speech, December 27, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - American Cancer Society, Inc. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - American Genetic Association (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1961-1968 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - American Institute of Biological Sciences, Quarterly Review of Biology (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Ashburn, Karl E., 1961-1966 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Associated Clubs of Woodlawn, 1964-1965 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Associated Rocky Mountain Universities, Inc., 1961-1965 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Association for the Advancement of Biomedical Education, 1961-1964 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Association of Midwestern College Biology Teachers, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Association of Suburban Conferences (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Augustana College (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Bartz, Robert (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Bell & Howell Canon Camera (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Brown University, graduate convocation, George Wells Beadle speaker, June 5, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Brown University, 200th anniversary, academic convocation and symposium, George Wells Beadle honorary degree, September 28 & 29, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - California Committee for the Improvement of Teacher Education (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - CBS, The Great Challenge program, February 10, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Childer, James Saxon (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory of Quantitative Biology (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory of Quantitative Biology, Delbrück Festschrift, September 1966 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Columbia University material, 1962-1966 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Commission on Undergraduate Education in the Biological Sciences (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Dickinson College, Priestly Award, George Wells Beadle recipient, lecture March 16, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Economic Club of Chicago, 1955-1965 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Ephrussi, Boris (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Executives' Club of Chicago, 1963-1966 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Fillmore Science Club, Fillmore Union High School (California) (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Freeman, William H., Freeman Foundation (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Furrow magazine (published by John Deere) (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Gell-Mann, Murray (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Genetical Society, 1961-1968 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Genetics, Incorporated, 1960-1967 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Genetics Society of America, Inc., 1961-1968 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Genetics Society of America, Inc., Mendel centennial, Fort Collins, Colorado, September 7-11, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 12)